LANRE AYENI

Contact no: +44 (0)771 2151 520 **E-mail**: lanreayeni2@gmail.com

Portfolio: lanreayeni.github.io/portfolio LinkedIn: uk.linkedin.com/in/lanreayeni

PROFILE

I'm entrepreneurial-minded designer who strives to execute every task to an exceptional standard. I have over 5 years of experience working on various web and mobile design projects as a freelancer. I strive to produce a unique end user product, which surpasses the expectations of clients. I posses first class interpersonal and networking skills alongside excellent attention to detail and time management as a result of working autonomously, as well as heading up small teams on a number of bespoke projects.

WORK HISTORY

FREELANCE PROJECTS

iComic app (Lead designer)

October 2014 - Present

- Created wireframes and mockups using tools like Balsamiq and Azure.
- Communicate user journeys and user flow to developer using tools like 'Gliffy' as well as traditional or conventional sticky notes and paper.
- Worked closely with developers and product managers to educate and inform about best UX practices.
- Research and investigate use cases to identify focus group for the app.
- Designed high fidelity User Interface using Adobe Photoshop and Sketch.
- Created UI elements and icons for app using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Rapid prototyped the app using the InVision application to test user flow before development.
- Worked on xcode's storyboards with iOS developers to make sure designs are consistent.
- Designed landing page for website.
- Created app logo, icons, onboarding and loading screens.
- Create engaging promotional content using Adobe Photoshop CS6.
- Designed layout for company's email newsletters using 'MailChimp' to subscribers.

SLNDR (Visual designer)

August 2014 - December 2014

- Created wireframes and mockups using tools like Balsamiq and Azure.
- Worked closely with stakeholders to educate and advice on best UX practices.
- Designed high fidelity User Interface using Adobe Photoshop and Sketch.
- Rapid prototyped the app using the InVision application to test user flow before development.
- Created UI elements and icons for app using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.

DryLake UK (Front-end developer & Designer)

Aril 2012 - December 2013

- Develop advanced applications of Business strategies using I.T skills
- Create engaging graphical promotional content using Adobe Photoshop CS4, CS5 and CS6.
- Use computer assisted designs (CAD) for product illustration.
- Upload files to the webhost's server using 'File Transfer Protocol' (FTP).
- Optimise web images for faster 'page load' time.
- Generate relevant 'keywords', adding metatags and H1 tags to pages for better search engine results
- Work on e-commerce packages such as 'Bigcartel' to create web stores.
- Analyse and Review website traffic using 'Google analytics'.
- Inventory management for products and services using Excel.
- Embed widgets and integrate social media feeds such as 'Facebook' and 'Twitter' and 'Linkedin'.
- Create and circulate company email newsletters using 'MailChimp' to subscribers.

Eve makeup & cosmetics (Front-end developer & Designer)

April 2013 - July 2013

- Discussed creative concepts for brand logos and worked with clients on developing brand identity.
- Created professional graphical designs using Photoshop CS4, CS5 and CS6.
- Developed an e-commerce website for an established makeup company.
- Programmed web pages using 'PHP', 'HTML', 'CSS' and 'JavaScript'.
- Used CMS to create a user-friendly backend for easy content management.
- Analysed and interpreted 'Google analytics' data to help determine page popularity, demography, web browser history and average number of page visits.
- Used 'PHP' and 'CSS' to configure 'Hikashop' shopping cart for consumer purchases.
- Integrated 'PayPal' as a payment method for secure credit/debit transactions.
- Utilised Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) to increase page ranking, drive traffic and identify target audiences.

EDUCATION / QUALIFICATIONS

2009 - 2011 BSc Computer Science; Middlesex University, Hendon

2006 – 2008 *LEVEL 3 BTEC National Diploma for IT Practitioners* **Lambeth College, London**

2005 – 2006 Advanced Website Management Systems **Lambeth College, London**

2004 - 2005 LEVEL 2 Diploma for IT Practitioners **Lambeth College, London**

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

- Highly confident user of all MS office and Adobe creative software packages (including Illustrator and Photoshop versions, CS4, CS5 and CS6) as well as a fully competent Internet user.
- Confident using 'Balsmiq' and 'Sketch' to design wireframes, mockups and user interfaces for mobile and web application.
- Experience working with GitHub and other version control applications like Bitbucket.
- Over 8 years experience with HTML, CSS and some knowledge of JavaScript, PHP, SQL etc.
- I prefer working on a Mac computer but don't mind Windows OS.

CORE SKILLS

- Takes an original approach to all tasks
- · Creative and logical thinker
- Ability to improvise and exercise own initiative
- Impeccable time management and organisation
- Highly analytical and self evaluative
- · Result driven and Solution Orientated

INTERESTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

I regularly participate in Hackathons and have been notably mentioned in the Metro Newspaper for my app concept.

As part of my personal upkeep I regularly attend the gym and have a keen interest in water-based sports particularly surfing.